Toronto, ON +1 647 914-4983 labdarafaela@gmail.com

About

I am a Software Developer with more than a decade of experience. **Proudly, Canada's permanent resident since 2019**. Web Development (Front-End Design) student at George Brown. Fluent in English and Brazilian Portuguese. Please, visit my portfolio at https://oliveirarafaela.github.io/my-portfolio/

Skils

Languages: Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and SQL

Layout system: CSS Grid and CSS Flexbox

Frameworks/Libraries: Bootstrap, jQuery, Hibernate, MVC (Struts), JSF, JSP, Angular

Databases: MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server

Tools: GitHub, Figma

IDEs: Eclipse, VS Code, CodePen

Others: Command Line, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Lightroom, Adobe Audition and Microsoft Word,

Microsoft Excel

Experiences

Business Data Analyst

ILAC

Sep 2018 – Apr 2020

The International Language Academy of Canada (ILAC) is one of the best-known English language schools in the world. For over 20 years, ILAC has offered international students a full learning experience, which includes English programs, exceptional customer service, exciting social events and a dynamic atmosphere.

Express Check-in Project:

- Collaborated with Compliance and Orientation teams to translate pre-existent data, plus weekly created data, into reports with achievable insights to the staff, material and procedures management applied to welcome new students. All this, using Microsoft Excel tool and SQL knowledge.
- In conjunction with those reports, I developed automated communication through MailChimp, to
 motivate new students to check some of the school's procedures and send us mandatory
 documentation in advance.
- The result of the execution of these actions was the increase from 10% to 60% of students arriving at school with registration already completed. This reduced the presence of the staff by approximately 50% on weekly orientations, compared with the achievement of the previous metric, diminishing operations costs without compromising the students' experience.

Environment: MailChimp*, Microsoft Outlook, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word *MailChimp allows adding some HTML tags to create email templates.

This job position has been terminated in view of the fact that the COVID-19 pandemic.

Software Developer

Indra Company

Apr 2012 - Aug 2015

Indra is an information technology (IT) services and consulting company. Through Indra, I worked at Sicoob, the only financial institution currently operating in Brazil through the credit unions system and coexisting in parallel with the traditional banking system.

- Sicoob Internet Banking, the project I was assigned to, was a web application compatible with Chrome, IE and Safari that offers banking services through a desktop web browser.
- My primary responsibilities were: solving bugs and coding new features using MVC architecture waterfall, HTML, Javascript on the Front End, Java on the Back End, and PL/SQL to connect to an Oracle database.

Environment: Microsoft Office, Eclipse, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Java, Oracle database

From September 2015 to April 2018, I worked directly at Sicoob as a contractor, with my duties maintained. This change was necessary to enable my immigration to Canada.

Data Analyst & Software Developer

Senergy Sistemas de Medição S/A

Jan 2010 - Mar 2012

Senergy offers and develops technological solutions that allow the availability of information related to the measurement of electricity, water and gas. My role enclosed two major phases: arrange and report data for our client CEB*.

- Phase one included cleansing collected data and guaranteeing its accuracy and integrity. My
 main task at this point was receiving a mass of data through Excel spreadsheets and
 transforming them into SQL queries to feed CEB's database.
- Phase two consisted of creating and generating reports using iReports, besides feeding
 dashboards o better present information to business teams and provide them with the possibility
 of data-driven decisions, diminishing issues with the power transmission lines maintenance and
 operation.
- In addition, it was also part of my duties be a Software Developer to solving bugs and create adjustments in Senergy's UI to better serve CEB. Such UI was coded using HTML, Javascript, Java, and PL/SQL.

Environment: Microsoft Office, Eclipse, iReport, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Java, Oracle and SQL Server databases

*The Brasilia Energy Company (CEB) owns and operates an electricity distribution system that delivers electricity to customers in the city of Brasilia, Brazil's capital.

Software Developer

TBM - Textil Bezerra de Menezes

Oct 2007 - Mar 2009

Textil Bezerra de Menezes is a settled in Brazil's global company in the textile sector.

- There, I designed and developed an automated machinery maintenance management system (here 3MS) that accurately provided forecasts about hiring, schedules, payment and turn-off of staff required for each maintenance team. The solution contained a barcode reader attached to a PALMTOP. Through it, data was collected by a UI built using struts MVC architecture waterfall, HTML, CSS, Java, and PL/SQL.
- 3MS's data processing and analysis returned, in real-time, who was working on which machine and when avoiding overlaps or non-authorized overtime.
- 3MS replaced a previous analog control system, granted data accuracy and promoted diminishing overtime payments of around 70% without loss of productivity during the first semester of use

Environment: Microsoft Office, NetBeans, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Java, Oracle database

Education

George Brown College

Postgraduate Degree, Web development

2021 - 2023

Front-End Design focuses on human-centred design to produce high-impact websites and apps. George Brown College's Web Development – Front-End Design program prepares learners with skills in both applications and interface development to deliver solutions that meet industry standards for practical code engineering and responsible design beyond traditional websites.

General Assembly Canada

Continue Education, Data Analysis

2020 - 2021

A strong foundation in Excel and SQL while honing techniques like cleaning data, framing questions, and data visualisation.

ILAC International College

Diploma, Service Excellence for Business

2018 - 2019

An essential fundament for Canadian workplace skills. Courses include customer service, human resources and leadership.

Universidade de Fortaleza

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science

2003 - 2010

All essential fundamental computing skills to solve complex problems and hone your innovation and creativity. Courses include calculus, logic, coding and software analysis.